when I was at CNN and CBS there's been
so many challenges you know this would
be a weeks long show I ain't going do
that to you how do you keep yourself
grounded then like if you're dealing
with like I mean we all deal with a lot
of challenges from a day-to-day basis
but how do you keep yourself what I call
it yeah so how how do you how do you
keep yourself grounded how do you keep
yourself sane how do you keep yourself
from thinking the sky is
falling well I I do believe in prayer in
the power of prayer you know so I pray a
lot I also am huge at listening to the
secret anything motivational you know I
go back and listen to a lot of the
interviews I did I remember when my
husband left me um I was 60 years old 60
I had just turned 60 and I remember
feeling like oh my God who's going to
want me now you know just really feeling
low um mom passed away a year later it
was just so much stuff going on and I
felt like I was wanted to give
up but then I remember but if I gave
up where does that leave me you know do
you want to continue being where you're
at or do you want to soar and at that
time my radio show was going good I was
interviewing people i' had been on CNN
and CBS I had started turning to M you
know learning how to make money and
things but there was a lot of personal
stuff going on obviously I've been
married for only 13 years and I was like
another one oh my God cuz people love me
men love
me they love to business me but when
they marry me it's like oh my God this
girl this lady she's too into business I
can be too business you know I don't I'm
I don't mind taking a risk and spending
my last $300 to go to a Jack Canfield
seminar if it's going to help me out you
know things like that that's why I say
this one's a winner because we go to
seminars together and we get each other
he's a musician he work with Michael
Jackson Prince and all that stuff KH
Clover hey
yeah yeah yeah yeah
so so in answer to your question I just
keep myself saturated or soaked I don't
know what's the right word with good
stuff you know stuff that's going to
push me past my pain to my power and
sometimes it's listening to other shows
you know interviews whatever it takes
you know I uh have a playlist on YouTube
with a lot of different gospel songs and
and just inspirational type songs so
sometimes when I get down I'll turn that
on you know I just find whatever it is I
love to
dance I love to
dance and so I will put happy you for
real song happy I love that yeah when
when people come to my Live Events we're
dancing all over the place on happy so I
love so how are you guys doing
today uh it looks like like my uh feed
is buffering right now but that's okay
that's technology we've been doing
dealing with this all week uh so folks
let me tell you hustlez Magazine's going
to be starting in um we are going to be
starting September 1st so you guys want
to pay attention and make sure that you
guys uh uh uh follow us through our
journey we're going to be entertaining
you with articles and video content from
your fellow entrepreneurs and this is
going to be the first living
documentary here on the hustle Zone and
the the the website is hustle Zone TV
now we would not be here without your
support so we got hustle Zone teas make
sure you guys check that out hustle Zone
um you get the hustle Zone hoodie
sweaters tank tops we have it all so uh
again uh we need your support support we
need you guys to help us out uh so
definitely check us out hustle zone.
courtesy of get that te um it's just
hard to spell that's why I purchased the
domain uh not that it's hard to spell
it's just really awkward talking about
it it's like get
that.com so uh we got uh and I want a
big shout out to Anthony
mclanahan uh to Ricardo McCrae Jason
Daniels uh Jamie Lynn and Shantel Lee
and there's more writers that are going
to be participating in the hustle zone
so I am super super duper excited
they're already writing content so um so
yeah that's that's that's pretty much it
so uh let me just take a look here who
is in the
building I don't see anyone in the
building yet but you know what the show
must go on right we don't just we don't
stop because some people not showing up
and you know you want to show up for
this for this for this round of the
hustle Zone because we have a special
guest so let's just see who's
in so Carla says good evening Ryan well
good evening Carla and Carla she is
we're almost ready to confirm her as
another writer of The Hustle song so who
else is next oh that's all there is okay
I I guess people on a Friday night in
May or sorry it's June 2nd I guess
they're all partying or something so we
got one like and folks please like and
share like and share like and share like
and share like and share because we have
a special guest here
tonight and she is okay first off let me
just tell you a little story so my
guest I would watch some of her videos
and I think we I we have mutual friends
and and whatnot but you know I've seen
her interview
celebrities business people that are
famous and you know she is funny because
she gets she has these funky glasses on
and she's like she gets her clients to
or she gets her guests to to dance and
and and and do all kinds of things in
her interviews but you know she's she's
someone that is a professional and she's
living her dreams you know this is what
the hustle Zone's about it's about
everyday living a culture of
entrepreneurialism where we all get a
chance to live our dreams and it doesn't
matter what time it doesn't matter what
time it is the time is now your mind is
your perception you create your own time
so uh the fact is is
that our guest is someone that is living
her dreams now you know so it was 23
years in the making okay she's she's
interviewed a lot of celebrities so
where we not going to get into so she's
she's interviewed Russell
Simmons okay from the popular movie The
Secret Lisa uh nickol or Nicholas or
Nicholls sorry I pronounced it bad but
you know what uh we'll move on Montel
Williams okay who grew up with Montel
Williams I did I did I did I did and the
list goes on and on and on and on so I'm
going to get her to tell her uh get her
to to come and talk about about her
history and whatnot and you know with
the hustle Zone we are we we talk about
the the the story leading up to the
glory we don't like to talk because the
glory the the usually success is
probably one the like the good part of
success is probably one fraction of all
that leads up to the success so I like
to talk about all that leads up to the
success so uh please
welcome
Miss Raven the talk show maven
woo what what so you're going to have to
unmute okay let me see if I can uh
get woo woo woo woo so how are you doing
Raven okay one second let me get your
audio here because for one okay there we
go I think your audio is check check am
I coming in okay yeah you are so how are
you doing I'm doing good hey everyone
hey I'll take these classes off now I
made my grand entrance so I'm going to
take them off so uh you know so I was on
your show earlier on this week and and I
guess the way that you and I met was
that you saw one of my videos and you
wanted me to come on and it was such an
honor because I would see I would see I
you know I'd see all your videos and I'm
like one of these days I'll be able to
interview celebrities and here is a
woman that had interviewed celebrities
wanting to to interview the hustle onong
so is such a pleasure to have you on the
show tonight Raven oh thank you for
having me you know I had to reach out
you know I that was the first time I
seen you and one of the things that I
talk about in my training is
professionalism and and how important it
is to think of yourself as not a talk
show host but a talk show preneur and do
the things that preneurs would do you
know give it that extra magic and you
know make it professional make it just
because it's live streaming podcast
internet radio so you act like you're on
CNN CBS MSNBC you name it and you did it
my man so you know know what what I got
to say
[Applause]
is thank thank you so much and I and
again I appreciate you uh you know just
I I appreciate the friendship and I
think you said you you you said
something yesterday you like you never
missed the mark on the people that you
surround yourself with and you've been
um very blessed with the people that
you've interviewed but before we get
into all of that um the first question
that I normally ask people and this a
very first question is and and and the
hustle zone is about you so you know the
very first question that we ask is what
is your story so start from the very
beginning I want to know from where
where did you grow up what how you like
a child everything back in the day we're
going back into dis so yeah we're going
we have to put we have to put the dis
because we gotta go way back I know
that's right well I'm from Cleveland
Ohio born and raised in Cleveland
Ohio and uh let me see when I went to
Shaw High School in East Cleveland um
played around a lot in school got in a
lot of trouble got in a lot of fights
you know I was just a bad
girl and then I transitioned from the
bad girl to wanting to be the cute girl
yeah so I got into did a little bit of
modeling no I wasn't tall enough or had
the high cheekbones or anything so I'm a
real creative person when somebody says
I can't do something I'm going to make a
way so I created my own uh fashion and
production troop it was called Raven
Blair and A Touch of Class models wow
and U so we did that for a while we were
uh magazine at that time was called Club
date magazine and they featured us then
I got married and I had a couple kids
that are grown now and got a grandson
and 20 as I was telling you ryy just
turned 20 last year be 21 this year I
can't even believe it
just hit my 66th birthday yay I'm still
here and I feel like I'm just beginning
just getting going and let me see I'm
trying to sum up everything been married
um four times I'm the married type they
weren't this one here is my soulmate and
he ain't going nowhere holding him for
Life he's going to be there with me
through all my senior years boy senior
citizen oh my
God I'll be the one that'll be 100 years
old with some glitter on the cane and my
hat and having a good
time dancing and stuff doing my Beyonce
dancing ain't no slow down for Raven
honey no doubt so have you always been
um you you you have a lot of energy okay
so when I go on to your your your shows
and I see the people that you interview
I mean you are on top when it comes to
to energy like have you always been that
kind of person that had so much positive
energy no thank you for asking that no I
was an introvert I um my parents were
very good parents but they were very
strict and if anybody that's my age or
close to my age you know back in the day
you get your butt whipped okay they
would call that abuse now make no
mistake okay with the switch with the
wet rag whatever it was and and so you
know I got a lot of whipping and you
know I um became an introvert very
easily it was scared to speak up um the
guys I dated in my teens and young adult
years they were kind of sit there look
cute don't say nothing so I began to
really really be just a huge introvert
scared to speak my truth scared to speak
up and um you know it was some dark
times dark times before I you know
things turned around for me like I was
telling you Ryan off air we um my life
didn't turn around until I was 55 years
old so up until that point you know it
was a lot of ups and downs in and out of
marriages um you know I did
telemarketing I so I come from cold
calling I was the one that would call
you and you'd hang up on and I call you
back and you hang up on I got good at
selling and I got very good at having
the gift to gab and very good at
listening and which served me a lot now
you know but it took all those years to
do that took years for me to find myself
I used to sneak to the radio station at
the age of 13 years old wjmo in
Cleveland Ohio yeah and I used to sneak
there uh which was uh not too far from
my house and then I remember one time
one of the um my mother them on a
restaurant chain of restaurants Blair
House restaurants and they had the radio
on and my mother came out of the kitchen
and someone said isn't that do isn't
that your daughter on the air and I'm
said hey I'm Raven Blair and I'm on the
air so that dream was there at 13 years
old but you know how dreams are big When
We're Young and then something called
life happenings and they begin to shrink
smaller and smaller and smaller until
you don't have a dream anymore and then
my dream found me at 55 years old at the
hospital while I was waiting for my mom
to get well she was an ICU unit and um I
had signed up for a course called tell
ainar secrets with the great Alex
mendian and I heard him say something
one day when I was sitting in the lobby
uh in the I guess you could say the ICU
Bo and I was on the phone on a
conference call and he said the quickest
way to become an expert is to interview
other experts and I'm like and then he
interviewed this guy by name of Rick
frisman that said he didn't do T
seminars he learned how to do this thing
called
podcasting and so I ran around the
hospital cuz I lived there for 3 weeks
while my mother was in the ICU unit and
I ran around and I told the um the
nurses I said I'm going to have a radio
I'm going to have a radio show I was so
excited about that you know I was so
excited about uhoh I did am I still in
frame yes something computer where I had
to move it okay so um I was so excited
about you know having a radio show and
it was right here at this ICU unit of
this Hospital Methodist Hospital in
Houston Texas there's my mom bless her
heart she's gone now but she lived 6
years after that and so um while sitting
at this hospital that's when you know I
heard um Alex say the quickest way to
become an expert is to interview exer
experts and that's what I began to do I
ran around the hospital I was so excited
Ryan you know what they said when
everybody goes home you can come back
behind the desk and use the office since
you're sleeping here just use the office
and do your research and I Google how to
do a podcast how to do interviews and I
started creating a a vision board and at
that time the secret had just came out
so I was putting you know all the
pictures from people on the secret that
I wanted to interview um my the actress
I wanted to interview Jane Kennedy and I
started building that and the dream just
got bigger and before you know it these
are some of the people I interviewed
Chile uh Russell Simmons Oscar W luasa
Jr Fran dresser monel Williams you know
um Jack Canfield Les Brown Lisa Sage
Brendan brashard I could go on and on
you know and um and it all started from
this Hospital wow never had any training
myself wow that's that's amazing but you
know like we were talking um we we you
and I were talking about passion and how
our desires are like like you know I
think I was saying it on your show that
desires are are are steam engines and
and they never die they just kind of
filter through different ways and the
fact that you're able to live your dream
like how does that make you feel um in
terms of Happiness like how do you feel
like do you wake up every day in Joy
like how do you feel oh my God I am in
so much joy when I think about myself
being an introvert one of the things I
kind of skipped over but I think it's
important because I want people to
understand you know that I didn't always
have this energy and my self-esteem was
like terrible so bad that during one of
my marriages I was so scared of my
husband um emotional abuse no nothing
physical but I was so scared that I
remember being in a closet looking at a
gun and really contemplating on ending
my life this was uh probably in the I
want to say mid90s you know and
so um I'm sorry I think it was more like
yeah it was in the mid earlier midnights
and I think about that all the time now
right I'm like what if I had done that
you know I'm so glad that God pushed me
past my pain to my power you know
because you know being able to interview
the greats you know one of the people
that I interview that always stays on my
mind because I read the book a lot that
was thinking Grow Rich of course
Napoleon Hill is gone but I had the
blessings of interviewing his grandson
several times Dr JB Hill and and Earl
nightingale's widow um Diana nigh Andale
is a good friend of mine and you know I
would have never met these people and to
be able to interview them you can't
interview them and some of that doesn't
rub off of you and now for me to be able
to pass it on and and teach it and train
it I wake up happy I wake up doing what
I I want to do remember I told you I
snuck to the radio station at 13 years
old and my story began at 50 my radio
Journey began at 55 so I always tell
people my my dream found me at that
hospital yes now and I was gonna ask you
so like I'm an
introvert I don't think I I stopped
being an introvert uh are you still an
introvert would you consider yourself an
introvert or are you you know I'm an
introvert a forc extrovert when I have
to be okay I think my power is I always
tell people I come alive behind the mic
you know I'm kind of shy um so it's hard
for me to do live streams and stuff I'm
more comfortable when I'm just on radio
you know I started doing live streams on
blab you know and so I'm getting
comfortable with it but um I would
definitely say I'm still an introvert
when people see me out you'll see me at
a table by myself and you know I once
the conversation starts and somebody
comes over with me I'm crazy raving like
forever but I do go into my introvert
shell but the my PO the
mic and I and I mean like for for for
those people that are not aware what
introvert is is an introvert is you know
they get their energy from you know from
being alone I get my energy from being
alone because like I deal with people
all day long and then there's a point
where I have to stop talking because I
don't want to talk to you anymore I need
to recharge we get bored really quickly
sometimes you know if I if I'm at a
party or you know at a big function I'm
I go in there with energy maybe if it
especially people that I know but then
after an hour or two like I'm so done
with
it you know like you said I'd rather
just go home and flip on the TV watch
the housewives or something for fun yeah
most definitely and so now growing up um
you've being a
bully and uh or not really a bully but I
wouldn't say a bully but you would get
into fights I would get into fights cuz
I had a lot of anger remember I told you
uh my parents were kind of they were
very strict right and so that I I had a
lot of stuff that was in me and so it
would quick to trigger the wrong thing
you know what I'm saying so I would want
get in fight for some reason I guess I
felt like I I don't know
you know that's where my power was back
then but it wasn't like I went and I
started the fight but if somebody came
across my path and they said something
that I didn't like or something like
that I'd quickly go off and you know and
that was just a lot of anger in me
because see one of the things that I do
know for a sure I've always been a big
dreamer and I've always wanted to to be
I used to tell I think I remember
telling my dad when I was younger to
build me a stage so always wanted to be
a star haven't quite got there but I get
to interview them so that counts totally
yeah so I always had that dream you know
saying I always knew that there was
something big for me to
do and I think that's why I was so
fascinated with the radio station and
you know people being able to hear them
all over the world and stuff you know um
and so I I think during that time I
wouldn't classify myself as a bully at
all cuz I never picked a fight but
but but you held your own I held my own
and there was a lot of anger in me you
know now going into um but I also ran
track and did a lot of positive stuff
too well you know and tell us about that
so I mean like with with all the things
all the positive things that you've done
you've um what were some of those
positive things you mean growing up yeah
oh well you I would say I was quick to
volunteer for different things I I ran
track uh used to do the 250 yard dash
yeah you know oh oh
yeah so I did things like that I used to
um always like to dance so I used to
have this little little small dance
troop and and I taught kids that were
like five I think was five and seven how
to do dance and they would use hat and
canes and stuff there's a very
theatrical side of me that's another
dream uh one of these days I'll fulfill
that too I'm thinking about doing a onew
woman show in 2018 so I'm going to I'm
going to unleash that uh I want to be a
star out of
me it's coming out get ready it's coming
out whether you want it or not yeah no
doubt and you you definitely have the
work to you know like I think that all
the things that you've done and all the
things that you've accomplished uh you
uh from reading up on you you were
you're
awardwinning uh talk show host so about
four or five times now yep I just got
one uh a couple I guess a month ago
where the rock star from a mastermind
Rockstar uh breakout trainer and
Rockstar radio host of the Year from The
Mastermind shout out to Craig desz wall
and um this is an award that my host
gave me it's called the giant award is
that nice yeah and so um I had to go to
um Atlanta and um my radio host cuz I'm
on the radio station now called amazing
women of power shout out to my amazing
women of power hoes yay and we reached
4.7 million listeners on the radio we're
iTunes radio station not a podcast and
so about a year ago they all got
together and they decided that they
wanted to nominate me to as their Giant
and so I got the giant Community Awards
and uh and all them they had little
videos I got to walk the red caret it
was really really nice
uh but prior to that you know I was on
CNN and CBS and you know um radio and
then I WL they gave me they made me host
of the year and then um I think for
three years I was one of the top 100
podcast so I've gotten my Awards and as
you know I just got my Barack Obama
presidential Lifetime Achievement Award
yay Raven yay Raven yay
Raven so tell us a little bit about that
wow like that's that's that's huge that
is so huge I I meant to have it over
here so I could show it but anyway um
that was a surprise my husband and I was
in Hawaii my son influenc to Hawaii last
year and I got this email saying you've
been nominated for the presidential
Lifetime Achievement Award and Ryan I'm
like yeah
right I'll just ignore this and they the
email kept coming you know we need to
they needed a full bio not a short one a
long two-page bio so that you know
something with the president president's
name on you you got they're going to
check you out you know cuz I was only
nominated you know and they do these um
around the country different ones and
you know um some sometimes there's in
one city there may be 15 in another city
there may be 30 but you have to be
nominated and you cannot nominate
yourself I thought it was a joke and so
when I got home um at the end of the
year uh I think it was like Jan right at
the end of the year January 1 or
something then it start they started
really sending an email say Hey you know
we need to go ahead and move forward
unless you just want to say that you
you're not interested in a nomination so
I picked up the phone because I was back
here in LA and I called them talked to
the people and asked them thousand
questions because I really didn't think
it was real and sent them everything and
I think I made it just like about a week
before he got out of office and that's
why they were rushing me because it
needed to have his signature on it and
they needed to check me out and do their
stuff so so I got it there on my wall
and I'm so so proud of that oh my God I
wish my mom and dad were alive for this
one yeah that's that's amazing but I
keep Mom and Dad close here's their
picture right there yay oh wow oh wait a
minute there you go yeah I got it here
let me uh zoom into that that's my
favorite pictures when we were kids
obviously they were young but that's the
favorite one I keep it right here next
to my dad's award cuz he was employee of
the year and I always keep this W it's
kind of Dusty for residents in a
Marriott so out of all the chains in
Marriott in when he was alive he got
this award it's a customer service award
and so I keep that as a reminder for me
to always give 200% in customer service
which I pride myself on doing that's
that's amazing Raven so um now with you
now owning your own radio show and and
whatnot how did you get into talking
your your radio station um how did you
get to talking to um celebrities cuz it
it seems like they're so far Out Of
Reach for a lot of us that um you know
we always it it we we think to to reach
them it takes pixie dust and you know
what me like everybody else thought the
same thing but I actually did that early
on before any of the awards before I I
wasn't even raving a talk show Maven
then I was just
Raven okay and um when I made up my
dream board at the at the hospital my
vision board I started just first of all
the people from the secret because I
would listen to that a lot at the
hospital keep me inspired and stuff and
then I put uh Jack Canfield on there and
um and Jane Kennedy that was the actress
and if you guys I don't know if you
remember Jane Kennedy but she was kind
of like the Halle Berry back in the day
okay uh African-American beautiful and
then uh you know I think she won a
beauty contest and then she became uh
actress and then uh also um she was uh
do they call him Sports women sports is
a sportswoman but back very few women
that were in sports that report the
sports you know and sports commentator
okay so she was someone that you know I
always just looked up to thought she was
beautiful in fact when I was younger Ron
you better tell me I look like Jane
Kennedy or we was for sure yeah I know I
look like Jane no I don't in fact Jane
and I are good friends now but um back
then I didn't know her but she was one
that I put her picture on my vision
board and I sent her someone um I think
I Googled at her name and someone said
that they were her cousin and I sent an
email and I let her know that I was also
from Cleveland and there's some other
commonalities that I mentioned there and
about four weeks later she sent me an
email and said hey homie let's connect
here's my phone number and stuff and and
that's how that came about so I teach
this thing to my clients called the ear
irresistible ask and you know I really
thought about some of the things that I
do um you know that makes a difference
for them where they'll more likely say
yes than no and it looks like Emma froze
okay then so it's about asking first if
you don't ask ask you want G get and you
got to ask in a way where they're more
likely to say yes to you than no because
they approached all the time as you know
Ryan everybody saying can I interview
can I interview can I interview you and
you got to think about what's in it for
them you know and they're you know what
is really in it for them and you're like
well you get to be on my show or you get
to be in my book or you get to be in my
magazine well you're not CNN and you're
not you know you know the Oprah O
magazine or anything like that you know
so you got to look at why would they
want to say yes you know and you know
that comes with your research and really
understanding you know what's important
for them and sometimes it's way be but
sometime it has nothing to do with the
advertisement it could be something
that's close to their heart ah I see so
um we're going to we're going to uh head
out for just a quick commercial okay and
then we'll be back so if you don't mind
to put yourself on mute that would be
awesome I sure will in other words shut
the heck up I will do
that what were some of the challenges
that you've had in running this this
business um and and running your Empire
yeah well first of all the biggest
challenge was um going from
free to some cha-ching cha-ching
cha-ching some money okay that was one
of the biggest challenges um once I got
started but prior to me getting started
the biggest challenge was staying
focused and staying in the game
and you know even when everything around
me was was collapsing I mean my husband
literally back then would put sticky
notes on my computer talking about he
wanted a divorce sticky notes who who
does that sticky notes sticky
notes
wow yeah so I had that problem and then
uh my in-laws at that time we had like
three or four that passed away um um on
the same date like a couple months apart
like one would die in November 16th and
then somebody else would die December
16th and then someone else would die
February March 16th it got so scary that
on the 16th we all would just say just
checking
in I mean that's not funny it's funny
now but it wasn't funny then it was real
okay that's how scary it was and then I
had to of course mother was in and out
the hospital you know sometimes she
would be brought back to the hospital in
a um ambulance almost com comos that was
very scary um and I was trying to do
shows and reach out for interviews and
all this stuff and it was a
nightmare and then I remember my
ex-husband at that time when I hear
somebody on TV say my wasb been at that
time wasb been at that time I think I
heard that on the braxon I love the
braxon and so um I remember we us
getting a letter in the e in um in our
start to say inbox in the in our mailbox
that gave us like 21 days or something
or we were going to be evicted from our
home wow and then that's when you know
and I didn't have any job and he was
working I said okay I got to turn this
around thinking I was going to save my
marriage okay ladies just telling I'm
just saying that don't work okay so
anyway um what I did is
I called a friend and she flew in her
name is martian Merl she flew in to
Houston we got a room in a hotel and she
showed me how to put a course together
and two weeks later I launched my
kitchen table radio course and I got
nine people in there to pay me I think
it was e
$297 and that's was exact amount you
know by the time all the nine people
paid whatever that total was the exact
amount that we needed to keep our house
from going into foreclosure and to
extend the loan so wow yeah so that
there was several different things and
then uh you know I did end up he did end
up um leaving years later but when I was
at CNN and CBS there's been so many
challenges you know this would be a
weeks long show I ain't G do that to you
list how do you keep yourself grounded
then like if you're dealing with like
cuz I mean we all deal with a lot of
challenges from day-to-day basis but how
do you keep yourself Happ what I call it
yeah so how do you how do you keep
yourself grounded how do you keep
yourself sane how do you keep yourself
from thinking the sky is
falling well I I do believe in prayer
and the power of prayer you know so I
pray a lot I also am huge at listening
to the secret anything motivational you
know I go back and listen to a lot of
the interviews I did I remember when my
husband left me um I was 60 years old 60
I had just turned 60 and I remember
feeling like oh my God who's going to
want me now you know just really feeling
low um mom passed away a year later was
just so much stuff going on and I felt
like I was wanted to give
up but then I remember but if I gave
up where does that leave me you know do
you want to continue being where you're
at or do you want to soore and at that
time my radio show was going good I was
interviewing people i' had been on CNN
and CBS I had started turning the M you
know learning how to make money and
things but there was a lot of personal
stuff going on obviously I've been
married for only 13 years and I was like
another one oh my God cuz people love me
men love
me they love the business me but when
they marry me it's like oh my God this
girl this lady she's too into business I
can be too business you know I don't I'm
I don't mind taking a risk and spending
my last $300 to go to a Jack Canfield
seminar if it's going to help me out you
know things like that that's why I say
this one's a winner because we go to
seminars together and we get each other
he's a musician he work with Michael
Jackson Prince and all that stuff
colleag Glover
hey yeah yeah yeah yeah
so so an answer to your question I just
keep myself saturated or soaked I don't
know what's the right word with good
stuff you know stuff that's going to
push me past my pain to my power and
sometimes it's listening to other shows
you know interviews whatever it takes
you know I uh have a playlist on YouTube
with a lot of different gospel songs and
and just inspirational type songs so
sometimes when I get down I'll turn that
on you know I just find whatever it is I
love to
dance I love to dance
and so I will put happy you for real
song happy I love that you know yeah
when when people come to my Live Events
we're dancing all over the place on
happy so I love to dance and I love what
I do and and it just keeps me uplifted
but I remember one time I was in such a
dark place I forget my ex-husband we had
a fallen out and I was supposed to
interview Jack Canfield for the first
time and the argument of my husband and
high was so
devastating it
it it oh my God just thinking about it
it just was devastating I don't know
what else to say it put me in a dark
place so dark I
remember just sitting in the
corner and just he had gone and just you
know just feeling like maybe I should
just stop doing the show if it's caus
and all this stuff I'm really not making
any money cuz that was back then I
wasn't making and I was like if I made a
couple hundred a month that was it and
and then the phone rang and it was Jack
Canfield and I had to do this show after
crying and sitting in a dark corner just
you know really evaluating myself
re-evaluating my life rather and I
remember I just snapped at it the minute
I heard his voice and I was like this is
I read this man's book this is the you
know this is one of the guys that
created Chicken Soup for the Soul I got
to snap out of it and I jumped up and I
pulled my chair over by my mic and I did
that interview and right at the end he
said he I asked him I said um you know I
really want to interview your friend
Mark Mark Victor Hansen he said I'll
send him an email and he said I'll copy
you on it so he sent an email to Mark
and he copied me on it and he sent a
testimonial and told Mark you got to be
on her show you know she's one of the
best interviewers I've ever had and and
then it just it just that that was it
that's all I needed once I had that it
was
on because that just let me know that I
was doing the right thing even though my
world was falling apart I was doing the
right thing and just keep it up and keep
it up and keep it up and so I still have
that letter he sent to Mark today with
my with that testimonial on it wow that
pretty then I've interview Jack three or
four times and he he actually said on
air um one time I interview him that
Raven you're the best interviewer on the
planet and I actually have that
testimony on audio where he says that
and he encourages people to be trained
by me and those type of things are just
Priceless when I think about the raven
that was in the closet thinking about
you know killing herself or I think
about you know Raven being devastated
cuz her husband walked out on her at the
age of 60 and all the other stuff that
happen as a child and stuff so I do know
that I was meant to do this and I I
don't have the perfect radio voice I
don't have all the techn the schooling
and stuff I just believe in going out
and being being you and be free to be
you and speak your truth and that's the
only thing I do so just a relationship
question advice or advice question here
is um I don't ask me nothing about
relationships I'm on the fourth
marriage but you know I I will never do
a relationship show I I I understand but
you know like what even with like making
those decisions because relationships
are really like for for Entre rurs you
know we don't really talk about them but
we need to find the right people in
order for our businesses to grow and for
us to be happy um yeah what you know you
you said four marriages
what like I I I'm afraid to get back in
like you know relationship because I you
know I left uh uh my my baby mom and I
broke up and it was really hard on me
and I still haven't really committed to
any relationship because I'm afraid of
going through all of that stuff again
you know what what gave you the fear or
what removed the fear for you to to to
do it again I'm a one person person one
one person's woman I don't date well you
know I don't you know I like to you know
I treasure who I am and you know I you
know my particular morals that's
important to me so I'm I'm not good on
the dating scene I don't want to date a
lot of people and so I you know I have
to be with that one person that's just
me I spent time single and I didn't like
it I thought there's a lot of games
people were playing you know and I
that's just not me and I believe in
marriage I you know I support marriage
that's part of what I've always wanted
as well I just need to find the right
person what I did didn't understand then
that I understood after my last marriage
was that you got to be very specific and
clear When you pray you can't just say I
want a man cuz you will get a man you
know you have to be very and that's in
business or everything so now I'm very
precise when I met uh khle um when I
before we got together I made a list of
on one side of paper was what I didn't
want on the other side it was what I
wanted and I was very clear I wanted a
man that you know had his own
business uh that he loveed to uh he was
a lifelong learner like me that we would
be able to go to seminars together and
we would be able to grow together I you
know I didn't like the the basketball
players and the people that already have
their money I never wanted to be in a
relationship like that I dated a couple
that's just not me cuz you know I want
to make my own money I want or me and my
husband grow together and make our money
so I was just very very specific on what
I wanted what was important to me in
this marriage and I got to say I got it
that's why I told you I'm not doing
anything on this computer because I
don't want to go wrong do anything
because he's he's an engineer and he
spends a lot of time setting that up I'm
like no I'm keeping this one I'm I'm
keeping this one but he makes it very
easy for me we both are you know are
building our business he's in music I
understand what he goes through he you
know I'm a talk show host and we both
know that you know we're building our
business we are in charge of creating
our own income and sometimes there'll be
good weeks sometimes they'll be bad
weeks I mean you know I things for me
right now are really good financially MH
but that's because I had to um flip my
mindset from thinking about myself being
a talk show host and now I had to
realize that I'm a talk show preneur I'm
an interview preneur you know because
that's the only way you can go from
Hobby to business you have to have that
preneur mindset or you'll keep treating
it like a hobby and that's what I had
been doing so now you know once I
flipped the script on that and I became
you know really good at um identifying
what made me stand out what I was really
good at what I wasn't good at and the
things that I was good at I became you
know I really thought about it and I
want to encourage your listeners to do
the same because I know you have a lot
of business listeners you know create
your own systems processes and formulas
you know get figure out what your secret
sauce is and then once you do that
that's when things will really be able
to accelerate for you because you you're
not just teaching other people stuff
although we all teach teach other people
stuff don't get me wrong but there are
things like my um I have something
called the icon interview formula see if
I have it here
um this is my formula that teaches you
how to go out there and get the I'm
trying to put this in the right screen
am is it in the screen yeah one second
let me uh switch
here okay go ahead okay so this teaches
people how they can go out there and get
top experts and I looked at what are the
things I did I investigate you know and
investigate before I ask most people
wait until after they get the yes and
then they investigate I teach my clients
how to go out there investigate first I
connect I learn you know I have a
special way of connecting with the
gatekeeper with the publicist with the
person that really has authority to say
yes or no and you know own your platform
I never say I have a podcast or a live
stream I say I have a radio show or I
have a uh you know uh uh TV show and I
want you to come on it now if they ask
me is it internet is it podcast I'm
going to tell the truth but you got to
act like you're at CNN CBS MSNBC you got
to speak with the power because what the
way you say it is the way they receive
it if you say oh I've got this live
stream on Facebook live and I really
would like for you to be on my show you
know you say hey I got this show it's
all about women empowerment you know I
was listening to something you said uh
uh on this particular interview I really
loved it and I said I have got to ask
Lisa Nichols to be on my show because my
listeners are going to love you Lisa
because you're all about no matter what
and that's exactly what our show is
about you see the difference you know
that's what's going to get them to say
yes and in here get to the nitty-gritty
they ain't got a long time so don't
waste their time so this was one of this
is my secret sauce another thing is my
Trinity interview my Trinity interview
uh we call it Trinity Triple Threat
interview process I teach people how to
be the oper in their Niche and and go
out there and host I teach people how to
be uh excellent guest on other people's
shows and turn other people's listeners
into their fans and then into buyers get
them to book um on your calendar and
then bring them to the third interview
interview them from on their you know
where they are now compared to where
they want to be and at the end close the
deal on a one call close no followup
required so those are just two of the
systems and processes that I
created well that's that's amazing
that's awesome thank you for sharing
that so we're going to close out here
with some close out questions what's
your favorite dish that you like to eat
my favorite what your favorite dish um I
I'm a steak lover you know steak yeah
yeah I like steak and and potatoes and
broccoli oh no asparagus I kind of I
like asparagus and I also like salmon so
it's a cross between the two and um how
are you with money are you Frugal uh do
you like to spend your money are you in
between no you know you know what some
women like diamonds some women like
pearls I like to invest in courses and
training my P my husband has to say you
bought another course or get in a
mastermind
so I'm not one to buy shoes or anything
like that I used to buy hats but as you
know I created my hat wraps now so I
don't have to do that so um yeah I'm
very frugal and what is your biggest pet
peeve my biggest pet peeve to be honest
is
um right now I would have to say my
biggest pet peeve is seeing talk show
hoes pour all that they do behind the
scenes in their work and they don't ask
for the
money because you know Ryan you know
even before we came on you know and I
know the work behind it but everybody
wants to be on our show I'm not talking
about the Stars I'm talking about
everyday ordinary people with
extraordinary stories and stuff they
want to be on our show and they deserve
to be on the show don't get me wrong but
this is a business not a hobby and have
overhead I'm sure Ryan youve put a lot
of money into equipment you know all the
things that I'm seeing you do behind the
scenes you know that takes a lot we go
through computers crashing and you know
right before we go on the show something
something happens I I remember having
Jack uh Mark Victor Hansen on Willie
jolly and about five really big guests
at the same time when I was on blab and
all of a sudden everything started
crashing around me I lost Mark and this
and that you know so it's a lot of stuff
and so my biggest pet peeve is watching
other host do such a great job in their
delivery and their content and stuff but
they they're
starving they're starving I know because
I was starving I get
it so what who are they asking for money
from from the guests from the that it
could be my guest pay me wow yeah you
know and what's their motivation I mean
I do my share of guess I mean you know
obviously Les Brown don't pay me
anything Alex mcdan but I'm talking
about everyday people that have
extraordinary stories if they want to
use your platform to come out and be
recognized as an expert okay um there's
a fee for
that wow I didn't I I personally didn't
know that I thought I just all through
commercial yeah yeah my radio host shout
out to amazing women of power they know
it they know it for sure but yeah you
know I this is what I teach and you guys
if there's any radio host there just
follow me on Facebook I have just set up
a new group as you know called Talk show
preneurs that's why I wanted you on
because of what you were doing and that
is strictly to talk to people about how
to ask for the money and how to take
their show from being a hobby to a
business and and and take themselves
have that mindset shift from thinking of
yourself as a podcaster or a live stream
or a you know radio um talk show host to
a live stream talk show preneur or a
podcast talk show preneur you know a
radio Podcast preneur you know what I
made a list the other day and that I
think I was up to um 22 different ways
to make money as a talk show host wow
yeah and I'm putting a course together
right now that will um share that as
part of my money map that's amazing so
we're gonna uh I want to just thank
thank you so much uh Raven for uh being
on the hustle Zone that was a very much
a pleasure and I definitely
learn I definitely learned some uh I
definitely learned some uh tips and
tricks from you on how to make my my my
you know my video uh podcasting into
something of a business I mean it's
already business because like um you got
your hustle t-shirts and all that stuff
you gotta that's why I had you Ryan I
already you know I told you I watched
how you were doing um your
professionalism is going to lead you to
business so you're at the point really
where people would gladly pay you to
come on if you just asked you know you
and I can have a private chat about that
oh yeah most definitely I I definitely
will I definitely will uh uh you know
ask you some more questions about that
but absolutely and I want to be a writer
I'm just going to say you know I want to
be a writer for the uh for your
hustle magazine hustle Zone magazine so
we definitely need to talk about that
and then I would like cuz we have our
amazing women uh magazine and I would
love for you to we do have an amazing
men section in the back that's Lisa
badass sass ofage on one of our covers
right there and uh we have a section in
the back you know where we have the guys
uh with their articles and stuff too
that's awesome I want to the first guy
on my cover who knows it may be
Ryan well it's got to be Ryan I
mean single dad you know I could talk we
may have to aover we may have to do a
cover swap or something well you there's
a lot you know you and our our
relationship is just beginning and I'm
so excited that I ran across hustle Zone
yeah that I'm so I'm again I'm so
blessed so thank you so much uh Raven so
if you don't mind to put yourself on
mute I'm going to close the show so all
right bye
so uh folks oh I'm in the wrong place
all right so yeah wow it's been like
over 44 minutes it's uh we I told her
half an hour but I I was lying because I
know how long these hustles on shows go
and they usually go over an hour hour
and a half because I like to talk and I
like to get everything I try to get as
much as I can out uh but as you can tell
with my guest uh she has a lot of EXP
experience and she doesn't waste no time
to make money you know she's out here
and she's grinding and for what she's
done you know it's inspiring that anyone
can get into it but you got to take your
business seriously and that's kind of
what I'm taken away from her story is
that you got to take it seriously you
got to be positive you know introverts
we're thinkers we sit there and we think
and Raven thought about how she was
going to go about it you know it was no
accident that she come stumbled across a
lot of these celebrities and you know
and that's the thing this is why the
hustle zone is here because we want to
tell the story behind The Glory we want
to we want to tell people the journey on
how people got where they are you know
so that you guys so we can humanize
ourselves and instead of us looking like
you know we're some pixie dust something
from that fell from the sky you know
we're human beings that have different
habits oh Raven before you leave there
is a tradition on the hustle Zone um I'm
going to do a call and response with you
okay um we do this for every one of our
shows uh I'm doing a collage of this but
um I'm going to say welcome to the and
then you're going to say hustle Zone and
you're GNA scream it as loud as you can
okay so I need scream it as loud as you
can so welcome to the hustle on
baby thank you so much Raven So
yeah thank you so oh PE out I keep I I
keep on like pressing the wrong buttons
here um hold on where where are we at
okay there we are so yeah so hustle Zone
baby so yes you guys definitely check us
out our links make sure you guys
purchase a a hoodie and and and help
support us we're going to be do going uh
we'll be putting together a GoFundMe
live um
uh we'll be doing a GoFundMe live
campaign um just so that because I would
like this is a living documentary I
would like to travel all over the world
and interview entrepreneurs um and and
document the the the times of their
credit cards decline you know I like to
hear stuff like that I like to hear
stories you know that really Propel
people to want to continue on with the
culture of being um entrepreneurs so uh
definitely definitely um you guys want
to uh if you want to support you want to
donate you want to sponsor you want to
have a commercial on the show hit me up
um Ryan at the hustle zone or no Ryan
hustle zone.com if you want to buy a
shirt from get that te it is um get
that. um if you want to buy a shirt as
hustle own. clo see it's been so long
now it's starting to trip up okay so
where's the credits here the credits
okay